<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="4" moduleid="185" modulename="journal" contextid="322">
  <journal id="4">
    <name>Set your Personal Goal for Teaching Self-Regulated Learning Strategies</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Set a goal for incorporating strategies for self-regulated learning (SRL) into your teaching practice. If you currently address and incorporate SRL strategies into your teaching, write a goal that either increases your focus on SRL in your lesson planning and design, or that refines your teaching practices to more effectively encourage students towards self-regulation. The purpose of setting a goal is to help you have an end in mind, i.e., a way to refine your practice of teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that your goal statements need to be specific enough to ensure change in teaching practice. View this &lt;a title="Refining Statements about Goals (or Objectives)" href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*167@$" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;resource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to help you set specific and measurable goal statements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting our success as teachers to our students' success as learners is a hot topic these days in educational policy in K-12. What's a fair assessment of student learning? Here is an example from one of the past course participants. She combines student feedback on her instruction and their own learning with level gains based on standardized tests:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of a goal for teachers:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;I would like to apply the writing improvement techniques and strategies I am learning in this course to the content of my classes, and assess after course completion which were effective, based upon my reflection and student feedback. I would like feedback from 50% of my students that they feel their writing has improved. I would also like them to witness level gains in their classes and their progress in meeting their own individual goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Math&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example of a goal for teachers: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I will apply the techniques and strategies I am learning in this course to the content of my math classes. At the end of the course, I will assess which techniques were effective using student feedback and my own reflection. I would like to receive feedback from 70% of my students that they feel their understanding of [math topic] improved. I would also like them to witness progress in meeting their own individual goals and level gains in their classes. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Example of objectives for students:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Given the dimensions of each room on a house floor plan (condition), ABE students (audience) will be able to calculate the number of square yards of carpeting required for each room (behavior) with 90% accuracy (degree). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Example of a goal for teachers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When introducing my students to new content knowledge or skills (condition), I (audience) will model one or more SRL strategies (behavior) and provide guided practice and gradual release for my students (behavior) until they can perform the skill independently (degree). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you've learned more about the importance of goal setting, monitoring, and attribution of effort to success, set a goal for yourself in teaching Self-Regulated Learning. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;Use the ABCDs of goal setting. Make sure the goal is tied to your circumstances, and reflective of your commitment to be a more effective teacher of adult learners. (Click Start or edit my journal entry)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <days>0</days>
    <grade>-4</grade>
    <timemodified>1516731928</timemodified>
    <entries>
    </entries>
  </journal>
</activity>